Mss.Rec.27 Mss.Rec.27
American Philosophical Society
New Familiar Abenakis and English Dialogues
1957
Mss.Rec.27
American Philosophical Society
5.0 Tape(s)
A reading of Joseph Laurent's New Familiar Abenakis and English Dialogues (St-Francis, Quebec, 1884). The author was a chief of the Abenakis Indians at the village of St. Francis, Quebec. The reader is the son of the author. Recorded in New Hampshire in 1957.
5 sound tape reels (7 hr., 51 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
Day, Gordon M.
Laurent, Joseph
Laurent, Stephen
Reel 1-5
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Stephen Laurent. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Abenaki language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - From title page through plejes, a pair of breeches, p. 26, 1957; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:13; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
    Scope and Contents note
    A reading from Joseph Laurent's _New Familiar Abenakis and English Dialogues_, (St-Francis, Quebec, 1884). The author was a chief of the Abenakis Indians at the village of St. Francis, Quebec. The reader is the son of the author.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Abenaki language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.; New Hampshire
  - From plejesal, plural of plejes, p. 26, thru wôbhagasak, carps, p. 39, 1957; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:15; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
  - From kikômkwa, sucker, p. 39, thru Paslid, Basil, p. 55, 1957; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:33; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
  - From Paslid, Basil, p. 55, thru nisinska taba pazekw kasta, 21 times, p. 80, 1957; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:33; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
  - From nisinska taba nis kasta, 22 times, p. 80 thru N'kizônkholônana n'tebaikizosôganna, we (exclusive) have sold our watch, p. 104, 1957; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:17; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
  - N'kizônkholônana n'tebaikizosôganna, we (exclusive) have sold our watch, p. 104, thru N'wôbigiji, I shall be white, p. 131, 1957; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:18; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
  - N'wôbigiji kizi, I shall have been white, p. 131, thru Aowak wigwômek, they are in the house, p. 162, 1957; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:07; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
  - Ôda n'-d-aiw, I am not, p. 162, thru kadopimuk, to be hungry, p. 184, 1957; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:16; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
  - Kadopi, be thou hungry, p. 184, thru 'wdoloak, they have a canoe, p. 202, 1957; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:08; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
  - Footnote, p. 202, thru the end, 1957; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:36:25; Day, Gordon M.; Laurent, Joseph; Laurent, Stephen
    A reading from Joseph Laurent's _New Familiar Abenakis and English Dialogues_, (St-Francis, Quebec, 1884). The author was a chief of the Abenakis Indians at the village of St. Francis, Quebec. The reader is the son of the author. "Note that the meanings of the names of the months on the last page of text was recorded together with the names on pp. 18-19."